petpeoplesplace.com 2016-03-15

# Privacy Policy | Help & Information | PetPeoplesPlace.com

_Last updated on 20th April 2009._

**This Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time.**

**We respect internet users' preference for privacy**  
At PetPeoplesPlace we take the security of users' information very seriously. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices of personal and non-personal information we collect when you visit our site. Our site is designed for people over 16 years of age. We do not wish to gather information from people below this age.

**California Privacy Rights ( _Applies to All Members_ )**  
Residents of California have a legal right to request and receive in writing or by email the names and addresses of all such third parties who received your personally identifiable information during the previous calendar year and a list of the types of personally identifiable information disclosed to such third parties. We extend this right to all members, regardless of the state or country laws by which they are governed.

**_Your personally identifiable information is never shared with third parties with the purpose of using such information for marketing purposes under any circumstances._**

To receive confirmation of this information in writing, please Contact Us.

**What Information We Collect**  
You can visit our websites, read articles and other materials, and check on offerings without giving us any personally identifiable information. So that we can provide our users and subscribers with the most efficient and enhanced, personalized service, we request information about you in certain circumstances, and also collect certain information automatically. For the convenience of our customers and to better serve you, a customer account includes all the collected personal information we may have, but you can update or correct your contact information or change your preferences about receiving offers and information from us or third parties at any time.

**Information Users Volunteer  
** We collect personally identifiable information, such as names, mailing addresses, and/or e-mail addresses, when you register to use our site. Occasionally, we may also request demographic information, such as age, gender, hobbies or interests. Often this additional information is optional or requested anonymously in connection with a survey. Website visitors may register to receive one of our e-mail updates, or to enter online contests and sweepstakes, and we may offer offline contests and sweepstakes as well. Registration is also required to participate in message boards, bulletin boards, or chat rooms at our website, and may be requested in connection with certain surveys. Registration forms will indicate what information is required and what information (if any) is optional.

**Subscriptions and Orders  
** If you wish to place an order for products or services online, you must generally provide additional information to that required for registration, such as your credit card number and credit card expiration date.

**Information Collected Automatically**  
We also may collect your IP address, browser type, domain name, access times and referring website address. This helps facilitate your online experience at our website. In addition, we use cookies to track usage patterns at our site and to control the display of ads, as well as to offer other functionalities (such as screening for age, helping to track items in your shopping basket at sites which offer online shopping opportunities, and "recognizing" you to speed up your log-in when you visit our sites).

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

**What We Do With Collected Information**  
We use information you provide to fulfill your requests and improve our publications, products and services. We may, from time to time, produce reports for advertisers, sponsors and vendors containing anonymous, aggregate information about our users and subscribers, such as demographic, age and online usage information. This allows us to provide content and offers that are most relevant to our subscribers and users and to work more closely with advertisers. We do not include any personally identifiable information of our users in these reports.

We use personal information so that we may display or send custom, personalized content to our website visitors and to send newsletters, mail, e-mails, features, promotional material, surveys and other updates, information or offers to our users and subscribers. A user may, at any time, opt out of receiving such information. We also use collected information to evaluate and administer our products and services, fulfill customer requests, like subscription and other orders, respond to any problems that may arise, such as delivery failures, difficulties in navigating our sites or accessing certain features, as well as to gauge user trends to determine what products and services are most popular with users.

**How Do We Share Personal Information?**  
Personal information is available to PetPeoplesPlace and its technical and fulfillment agents and consultants who make this site and our publications, products and services available to you. Anonymous information is available to our advertisers, sponsors and promotional and business partners. PetPeoplesPlace may access both anonymous, aggregate demographic data and any personal information you provide for internal marketing purposes, including sending you notices of subscription renewal deadlines, new publications, services or products we offer likely to be of interest, and filling subscription and other orders. There are many companies who may be required to assist us in making our publications, products and web sites available to you. Web host firms, technical and database consultants, advertising agencies, and fulfillment firms, including firms assisting us in offering contests and promotions, may have access to personally identifiable information in the course of making our products and services available. All companies working for PetPeoplesPlace must comply with our information collection, use and disclosure policies, and are not permitted to sell your information to third parties or to use it except as authorized by us and you, or as permitted or required by law.

**_Your e-mail address is not shared with third parties with the purpose of using such information for marketing purposes under any circumstances._**

**Public Domain**  
You should be aware that if you voluntarily disclose information, personal or otherwise, online in any community area (whether through our website or any other service available online), that information can be collected and used by others. For example, if you use chat, forums, bulletin boards or message boards, or if you post personal information online (such as your e-mail address), you may receive unsolicited messages from others. PetPeoplesPlace has no control over this use of your personal information.

**Legal Disclosure**  
We reserve the right to use or disclose any information without notice or consent as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request; to conduct investigations of consumer complaints or possible breaches of law; to protect the integrity of our site and our property; to protect the safety of our visitors or others; to fulfill your requests; or to cooperate in any legal investigation.

**Your Rights**  
We will always respect your wishes. If you wish to opt out of our newsletter and partner emails, log in to your account and change your settings. If you wish to update any of the details we may have about you, you can do so by logging in to your account and changing your saved details. If you no longer want us to store any information about you, you can request that we delete your account. However, if you want to continue to use features of our site that require registration, we will not delete your account. We will take commercially reasonable steps to implement your opt-out or account deletion requests promptly, but you may still receive promotional information from us by e mail for up to 10 days due to processing methods.

**Security of Your Personal Information**  
We incorporate standard industry practices internally and with our service providers suitable to the degree of sensitivity of the information involved to maintain the security of your personal information and to avoid its disclosure except as described in this policy. Your personal information may also be protected by the password you created when you registered at one of our websites where this feature is offered. The confidentiality of any password is yours to protect. You may change it anytime by following the instructions at the website where you registered.

**Security of Your Personal Information**  
We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt important information, such as your credit card data, in an effort to prevent unauthorized access during transmission of your orders over the Internet. Although we use our best efforts to assure that your data remains secure when maintained by us, security during Internet transmissions cannot be assured. We store data on multiple service systems, in controlled, secure environments.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

**Following External Links**  
PetPeoplesPlace may offer links to or from Web sites it controls to other sites operated by third parties so that you can conveniently visit our vendors and advertisers or locate other content likely to be of interest. We are not responsible for the content, practices or policies of sites operated by third parties and urge you to inquire about them before providing any personally-identifiable information.

**Changes in Corporate Structure**  
In developing our business, we might sell certain assets, or the company, or parts of it, may be sold, merged or otherwise transferred. In such transactions, user information, whether personally identifiable or otherwise, may be one of the transferred assets.

**More Information**  
If you require further information, help in understanding our policy or have a request for account deletion, please Contact Us.
